SURAJ ACHARYA

Moldegata 23 H0103, Oslo Email: surajacharya996@gmail.com Cell phone: +4746554210 Date of Birth: 10/08/1991

Nationality: Nepalese

GitHub: https://github.com/surajacharya62

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/suraj-acharya

SUMMARY

Three years of practical experience as a SQL and BI developer who has analyzed complex datasets, identified trends, and provided useful insights. Strong in SQL query optimization and data-driven decision-making. To make use of my abilities in data modeling, data warehousing, data visualization, ETL process, and BI development, I'm currently looking for a full-time Data Engineer/Data Analyst position and committed to generating insightful data that aids in making valuable decisions and enhances corporate effectiveness.

KEY QUALIFICATION

- MS SQL Server, MSBI(SSRS,SSIS,SSAS),Data Warehouse, Power BI, Data Modeling, ETL pipeline
- SQL, Azure SQL Database, Azure Synapse Analytics, Azure DataFactory, Azure DataBricks, T-SQL,
- Python, GIT
- Machine Learning(scikit- learn), Pytorch

WORK EXPERIENCE

Student Assistant

Oslo-Metropolitan University, Oslo 01/2023-Today – 6 Months

- Collaborated with Data Engineering students on data analytic projects, focusing on in-depth data analysis, identifying trends, patterns and correlations to provide actional insights and recommendations using various tools such as Python, Pandas, Matplotlib and Seaborn.
- Developed and maintained data models and statisticals models to predict and forecast for best outcomes.
- Demonstrated problem-solving skills, tackling data challenges while fostering a dynamic and knowledge sharing environment following data analysis best practices.

Research Assistant

Oslo-Metropolitan University, Oslo

Oct-Dec 2023 - 3 Months

Responsible for analyzing data using Python libraries (SQL,Pandas, Matplotlib, Streamlit) as part
of the Artificial Intelligence Journal team to develop an Early Warning System for ethical
investigative journalism using Data Science techniques supported by The Research Council of
Norway Fritt Ord Foundation.

SQL Developer

Jyoti Bikash Bank, Nepal Jun 2019-July 2022 – 3 Years

Link: Jbbl.com.np

- Contributed to the development of a comprehensive Power BI dashboard within a data team to visualize and analyze the overall bank loan and deposit performance using various database system such as MS SQL Server, PostgresSQL.
- Developed diverse SQL and T-SQL reports and maintained a data warehouse using an ETL pipeline and database mail system for report automation and data analysis.

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Applied Computer and Information Technology Specialization - Data Science (2 Years program) - Full Time

Oslo-Metropolitan University, Oslo

August 2022- Expected graduation July 2024 Completed First Year

Master's degree in computer application (3 Years program)- Full Time

VTU University, India

NOKUT Approved (equivalent to Norwegian two years master's degree) - <u>view</u>

August 2014- July 2017 Thesis title: MyEasyRide

Worked as an intern (Purple Photonic Solutions LLP) in a team to develop ride sharing applications using online portal system. This application is mainly focused on employees who belong to the same IT park building. It notifies the application using employee to share the ride for other employees who requests from the nearest or same location. It uses the shortest path algorithm. It is built on Java Server Face web framework and MS SQL Server database.

CERTFIFICATES

- Certified Data Scientist- International Association of Business Analytics Certification (IABAC)-Netherlands- view
- Data Science Foundation-International Association of Business Analytics Certification (IABAC)-Netherlands- view
- Power BI Business Intelligence, Skill Best, Nepal-view
- Foundation program: Programming, Database, Software Engineering, Infosys, India — view
- Microsoft Certified: Programming in HTMS5 with JAVASCRIPT and CSS3 – view
- Attending the training course for Azure Data Engineer certification(Udemy-Eshant Garg)

LANGUAGES

English: Good proficiency

 Norwegian: Attending the course A1 and A2 Level at OsloMet

- Nepali: Native

- Developed and maintained data models and schema designs for data warehousing solutions, optimizing query performance and data accessibility.
- Created interactive dashboards and reports using Power BI, enabling stakeholders to access and understand key metrics.
- Developed and optimized SQL and T-SQL queries, stored procedures, views and functions to support application development and data manipulation.
- Collaborated with business user, collected requests and updated existing BI reports to accommodate evolving business needs.
- Leveraged live transaction databases, for extracting and presenting real-time data for reporting purposes.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to understand data requirements and deliver analytics solutions that supported business objectives.

Junior Software Engineer

In Time Tec Visionsoft Pvt Ltd, Bangalore, India Jun 2019-July 2022 – 5 Months

Link: in time tec Client: balsamhill.com

Worked as junior software engineer in a Salesforce team for development of web-based e-commerce application for selling the Christmas trees for the client *Balsam Hill*. Built using Salesforce platforms' administrative wizards on button click, Apex programming for developing the server-side, inbuilt database features for storing the data. This application facilitates the CRUD operations on all sales related details. It includes the web pages for creating customer, editing, displaying, shipping and orders and various other details.

Intern

Rubixe,Bangalore, India Feb-Sep 2022 – 8 Months

Link: rubixe.com

- Collaborated on the Employee Performance Analysis project with a data science team.
 Conducted problem understanding, data mining, trend identification, analysis, and report generation. Applied diverse machine learning algorithms for informed business decisions and monitored model performance.
- Sample code: https://github.com/surajacharya62/EmployeePerformanceAnalysis

MACHINE LEARNING PROJECTS

- HeartDiseasePrediction- <u>View</u>
- PredictingUsingAgeUsingTransferLearningOnEEGSignals-View
- EmployePerformanceAnalysis- View